<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Flights connections and regional reviews of global airports ✈️ on Computational Social Science Project (Group 2)</title><link>https://kommodeskab.github.io/SocialProjectWebsite/</link><description>Recent content in Flights connections and regional reviews of global airports ✈️ on Computational Social Science Project (Group 2)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://kommodeskab.github.io/SocialProjectWebsite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data description 📊</title><link>https://kommodeskab.github.io/SocialProjectWebsite/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kommodeskab.github.io/SocialProjectWebsite/data-description/</guid><description>Where did we get the data? The data was (mainly) acquired from openflights.org, which hosts a handful of interesting datasets surrounding aerospace and transportation. Other than that, we found text reviews of airports from Skytrax, and info about continents of countries and BNP per capita of countries from Our World In Data. We used the following datasets:
airports.dat: The ID, city, country, and much more information (13 attributes) of 7698 airports all over the globe.</description></item><item><title>Network analysis 🕸️</title><link>https://kommodeskab.github.io/SocialProjectWebsite/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kommodeskab.github.io/SocialProjectWebsite/network-analysis/</guid><description>Using the collected data, we constructed a network of international airport connections. Each node in the graph is an airport, and each edge is a flight between the airports. The weight of each edge is the number of flights on that route, and the degree of each node is the number of connections to other airports. Each node/airport also have a set of attributes collected from the data:
City Country Latitude Longitude Airport name Continent BNP per capita Using the latitude and longitude, we were able to visualize our graph using each nodes spatial position.</description></item><item><title>Text and review analysis 📖</title><link>https://kommodeskab.github.io/SocialProjectWebsite/text-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kommodeskab.github.io/SocialProjectWebsite/text-analysis/</guid><description>Finally, we wanted to analyze and visualize the numerical ratings of the airports around the world. We wanted to get a general view of how airports are rated all around the world. Therefore, we decided to fit a Gaussian Process to the dataset, such that the input features are the latitude and longitude coordinates of the airports, and the target variable is the fraction of positive reviews. Therefore, the target values falls in the range [0, 1], where 0 means no positive reviews, and 1 means only positive reviews.</description></item></channel></rss>